A Guide to the IAWA Small Collections, 1907-2013
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
IAWA Small Collections, 1907-2013
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2009-054
31.9 cu. ft. 22 boxes; 40 oversize folders
The IAWA Small Collections was compiled from a variety of sources by Special Collections staff for use in reference and research. The collection consists primarily of biographical materials for women architects, architectural historians, and designers including curriculum vitas, firm brochures, exhibit notices, photographs, and publications. Drawings, sketches, course notes, correspondence, and other materials pertaining to architectural collections are also present.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The IAWA Small Collections is an artificial collection compiled by Special Collections in 2009.
Alternative Form Available
The Special Collections Imagebase contains digital images from the following collections:
Brians, Audrey papers, 1951-1952, 2001-2002, 2008
Driskel, Jean Roth papers, 1949-1958, 1968-1971
Galster, Gertrud publications, 1963-1988
Keichline, Anna Wagener papers, 1991-2004
Lari, Yasmeen curriculum vitae and CD, 1992, 2003
Marquard, Claudia posters, 1998
Marshall-Baker, Anna papers, 1997
Speigel, Susan postcards, 1985
Stan, Sally Bould biographical material, 1972, 2006, 2008
Steinmesch, H. May papers, 1946, 1967-1968 and undated
Sutton, Sharon E. artwork, 1976-1979, 1999
Historical Information
The International Archive of Women in Architecture (IAWA), established in 1985, is a joint program of the College of Architecture and Urban Studies and the University Libraries at Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. The purpose of the Archive is to document the history of women's involvement in architecture by collecting, preserving, storing, and making available to researchers the professional papers of women architects, landscape architects, designers, architectural historians and critics, urban planners, and the records of women's architectural organizations.
Scope and Content
The IAWA Small Collections was compiled from a variety of sources by Special Collections staff for use in reference and research. The collection consists primarily of biographical materials for women architects, architectural historians, and designers including curriculum vitas, firm brochures, exhibit notices, photographs, and publications. Drawings, sketches, course notes, correspondence, and other materials pertaining to architectural collections are also present.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically into three series Persons and Associations, Publications, and Subject Files.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Several collections within IAWA Small Collections relate to larger holdings within the IAWA. A see also note located within the collection's description will alert the researcher to additional materials.
Separated Material
These publications were cataloged separately in the Addison library catalog, and are available through the Special Collections Reading Room:
American Architectural Foundation. That Exceptional One: Women in American Architecture, 1888-1988. Washington, D.C.: American Architectural Foundation, 1988. NA1997 .T47 1988 c.3
Bay, Helle. Women in Danish Architecture. København: Arkitektens, 1991. NA1997.W66 1991
Gruft, Andrew. Patkau Architects. Barcelona: Gustavo Gili, 1997.
Khazanova, Vigdalia. Soviet architecture during the first years after the October, 1917-1925. 1970.
Mang, Karl, and Wend Fischer. The Shakers: Life and Production of a Community in the Pioneering Days of America: an Exhibition by the Neue Sammlung, Munich: [Catalogue. Munich: Die Neue Sammlung, 1974.
Markelin, Ulla. Profiles: Pioneering Women Architects from Finland. [Helsinki]: Museum of Finnish Architecture, 1983. NA1455.F5 P76 1983 c.3
Matrix (Organization). Making Space: Women and the Man-Made Environment. London: Pluto Press, 1984.
Matrix (Group), and Greater London Council. Building for Childcare: Making Better Buildings for the Under-5s. [London?]: Published jointly by Matrix and GLC Women's Committee, 1986.
Sundt, Elise, and Monika Klenovec. Ziviltechnikerinnen. Wr. Neustadt [Austria]: Druck- und Verlagsanstalt Gutenberg, 1982. NA1997 .Z58 1982 c.3
Winter, Friedrich Gottlieb Maximiliam. Bauten und Ziele. Krefeld: Scherpe, 1970.
Index Terms
Persons:
Adamczewska-Wjchert, Hanna; Alexander, Dorothy Baxer; Almedia, Marília Sant'Anna de, 1948-; Anisimova, Irina; Antonakakis, Susana; Baptista, Angela; Bassett, Florence Knoll; Bausman, Karen; Bentel, Maria A.; Bethune, Louise Blanchard, 1856-1913; Bevington, Christine Benglia; Binder, Rebecca L.; Biriukova, Alexandra; Birkby, Noel Phyllis; Bizios, Georgia; Bliss, Anna Campbell; Bo Bardi, Lina; Boden-Archer, Dendron; Bodmer, Monica; Bolldorf-Reitstätter, Martha; Bonney, Claire; Borecka, Eva; Bragstad, Susan; Brains, Audrey; Brierly, Cornelia; Brosowsky, Bettina Maria; Brotons de la Nuez, Rosa Maria; Browne, Charlene; Browne, Jennifer; Budevska-Salcheva, Nadezhda; Budis, Sanda; Bulant-Kamenova, Aneta; Campana, Ana; Cardenas, Eliana; Carlini, Erdmute; Chestnutt, Rebecca; Chowdhury, Urmile Eulie; Christianovic, Ruth; Ciocanea, Doina Marilena; Cline, Ann; Cole, Doris; Colter, Mary; Cooper, Margaret Robb Shook; Cornelius, Ulla; Cutler, Sherrie S.; DeGezelle, Molly; Delavrancea-Gibory, Henriette; Demi, Engjellushe Hoxhe; Diaz, Luz Maria Beristain; Dietrich, Verena; Dombai, Maria; Donev, Miriana; Dougherty, Betsey Olnick; Dow, Joy Wheeler; Drew, Jane; Driskel, Jean Roth; Enriquez-Musni, Marjorie L.; Fallon, Kristine K.; Fessas-Emmanouil, Helen; Figueira, Leonor; Filas, Hilde; Fisher, Laura A. Horstman; Flagger, Ingeborg; Flecken, Ursula; Forsthuber, Sabine; Fritz, Sylvia; Gabrea, Georgeta; Galster, Gertrud; Getov, Alexandrina; Glebova, Tatiana; Gottwald-Thapar, Sylvia; Gray, Eilen; Griffen, Marion Mahony; Grisogono, Ksenija; Groat, Linda N.; Guillissen-Hoa, Simone; Hadid, Zaha; Hafer, Hannalore; Hahn, Ivanka Vulchanova; Hakala-Meyer, Maija; Hanna, Browyn; Hansen, Fani Danadjieva; Hautman-Kiss, Klara; Hayden, Florence Kenyon; Hebald, Margo; Helg, Franca; Hermanuz, Ghislaine; Herrmann-Chong, Evelyn Chi Chain; Hillebrande, Lucy; Himanen, Marina; Holt, Rengin; Hook, Mary Rockwell; Hooker, Marjorie Mead; Hosken, Franziska Porges; Hubacher, Annemarie; Huber, Verena; Ison, Leonara; Jauch-Stolz, Monika; Jirmunsky, Galina, 1929-2010; Kazakova, Liumila; Keichline, Anna Wagener, 1889-1943; Kemp, Diane Legge; Kennedy, Louise St. John; Keremidarska, Svetlana Lazarova; Khazanova, Vigdalia; Khokhlova, Larisa; Kingsley, Karen; Kiss, Katalin; Klingelhofer, Petra; Koci, Ilse; Koci-Montanari, Silvia; Korobina, Irina Mikhailovna, Dr.; Koulagina, Helen Albertovna; Kuhler, Ingeborg; Kurian, Elizabeth George; Lambert, Phyllis; Landry, Jane L.; Lang Jakob, Evelyne; Lari, Yasmeen; Lassmann, Edith; Lemos, Maria Joana Viana de; Levine, Sally; Lin, Maya; Lipsey-Rahe, Georgina; Loffler, Anthusa; Lourida, Sophia; Lyon, Virginia; Macfarlane, Jane; Magee, Fannie; Maiz Apellaniz, Marta; Mang-Frimmel, Eva; Marquard, Claudia; Marshall-Baker, Anna; Martin, Shelley F.; Matsukawa-Tsuchida, Junko; Matsuzaki, Eva; Mendelsohn, Louise; Meredith, Amaza Lee; Merle, Ulla; Miculinic, Sonja; Mikic, Vesna; Moller, Alice Finnerup; Moody, Harriet; Moody, Mildred; Muller, Cornelia; Muller-Schmid, Catherine; Muntoni, Alessandra; Mykolyk, Mary; Nakahara, Nobuko; Nanasy, Ilona; Novakova, Zdenka Marie, 1939-; Nowicki, Stanislawa; Okhotina, Nina; Ozkose, Aysun; Patkau, Patricia; Patrulius, Irina; Pattison, Harriet; Pavlova, Luidmila Pavlova; Pavlova, Radka; Perriand, Charlotte; Petrova, Iskra Nikolova; Pidgeon, Monica; Pierce, Marjorie; Pietila Raili; Pingel, Gerda, 1954-; Pinos, Carme; Plumb, Helga; Popova, Rositsa; Portugali, Nili; Praun, Anna-Lulja; Prochazka, Elsa; Rachel, Shalit; Reese, Ilse Meissner; Ribariva, Elisaveta; Riggs, Lutah Marie; Robertson, Donna V.; Rueschemeyer, Marilyn; Rysdale, Anne J.; Sachs, Lisbeth; Sankalia, Hema; Santos, Alda; Sarantsatsral, Ochirpurev; Scarlette, Shannon Taylor; Schmidt-Kirchberg, Barbara; Schmidt-Thomsen, Helga; Schutte-Lihotzky, Margarete; Scott Brown, Denise; Seifen, Barbara; Seixas, Maria Fernanda Machado; Sepic, Liljana; Shackelford, Grace; Shayo, Anna; Simon, Cathy J.; Sion, Maria Militza; Sklarek, Norma Merrick, 1928-2012; Slunkova, Inessa Nikolaevina; Smith, Cloethiel Woodard; Smolina, N. I., Nadezhda Ivanovna; Spear, Laurinda; Speigel, Laurinda; Stamatova, Nadya; Stan, Sally Waldner Bould; Steinegger, Elisabeth; Steinmesch, H. May; Stevens, Mary Otis; Stocker-Mergenthaler, Beth; Stoilova, Ljubinka K.; Sutton, Sharon E.; Svigelj-Cernigoj, Monjca; Syrkus, Helena; Taranto, Lisa; Thompson, Jane; Tolzer, Maria; Toma, Nicoleta; Topelson de Grinberg, Sara; Tranberg, Lene, 1956-; Treant-Mathe, Juliette; Troeva, Vesselina Rousseva; Tsevelma, Danzansharavyn; Tyutcheva, Narine; Uncu, Ana; Urbanke, Rosemarie; Vecsei, Eva Hollo; Veltcheva, Maria; Vilches, Cecilia; Vinciarelli, Lauretta; Vitzthum, Sandra; Vytlacil, Anne; Wagner, Anne Gabriele; Wainstein-Krasuk, Olga; Weisberg, Sarelle T.; Weiss-Koenig, Annaliese; Whitman, Bertha Yerex; Wilburn, Leila Ross; Winchester, Sarah Pardee; Winter-Bracher, Ingeborg; Wood, Joan; Xiaowei, Luo; Zaglaniki, Loukia; Zahle, Mette
Corporate Names:
American Institute of Architects. Women in Architecture.; American Institute of Architects.; Association of Collegiate Scholars in Architecture.; Matrix: Feminist Architectural Co-Operative Limited.; Newcomb College.; Vermont Design Institute.; Virginia Women in Architecture: An Exhibit Highlighting the Work of Women Architects in Virginia.; Women's Design Service.; Women's Development Corporation. (R. I.); Women's International Network.; Women's School of Planning and Architecture. (Sophia Smith Collection at Smith College)
Subjects:
Architects and community; Architecture--Study and teaching; International Archive of Women in Architecture (IAWA); Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University; Women-owned architectural firms.
Genre and Form Terms:
Architectural drawings.
Occupations:
Architects.
Contents List
- Persons and Associations
  - Adamczewska-Wjchert, Hanna, biographical papers, 1985-1987 and undated, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet. (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Born 1920. Architect of Warsaw, Poland; Professor at the Warsaw Technical University. Materials include a lengthy curriculum vitae, reprints of articles she wrote about urban projects in Poland, and a 1985 catalog she wrote, "Formation of Pertinent Housing Cooperatives."
  - Alexander, Dorothy, photographs, 1974, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 10)
    Architect in her firm, D. B. Alexander. Projects have included commercial remodeling for the Arriflex Corporation, Panavision and the Jack Tilton Gallery. Staff photographer for Oculus, the magazine of the New York Chapter of the American Institute of Architects. The collection consists of a set of photos entitled "White Flowers" that were used as the opening image of a chapter in Women in Architecture, edited by Susana Torre. See also the ALEXANDER, DOROTHY, ARCHITECTURAL COLLECTION, 1939-1994 MS2008-089.
  - Almedia, MarÍlia Sant'Anna de, papers, 1990 and undated, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 6)
    Architect in Brazil. Collection includes résumé and magazine articles, including "To Hear the Mermaids: MarÍlia Sant'Anna de Almeida and José Magalhaes Junior: Teatro Municipal, Sao Sebastiao-SP." [Translated from "Para ouvir as sereias" and locally available.] Inventory available.
  - American Institute of Architects, 1990-1999, Extent: 0.3 cubic feet (Box 9)
    The American Institute of Architects is an organization consisting of 300 chapters designed to serve the needs of architects at the national, state, and local levels. The collection consists of programs for chapter meetings, lecture announcements. The collection also includes information about lectures publication, program agendas for committees within the AIA, specifically the WIA (Women in Architecture).
  - Anisimova, Irina, biographical papers, 2008, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 1)
    Biographical sketch, bound booklet entitled "Multistoried apartment houses for Moscow design by Professor Irina Anisimova" dated 2008.
  - Antonakakis, Susana, papers, 1987, 1994, and undated, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 1)
    Born in 1935. Architect in Athens, Greece, and a founding member of the architectural firm Atelier 66. Materials include a copy of a lecture she gave in 1987 in Delft, the Netherlands, to the International Design Seminar; a postcard for an exhibit in Zurich, Switzerland, of the work she has done with her husband, Dimitris; and a brochure of the Mavrakakis house in Perdika, Greece, which she and her husband designed.
  - Association of Collegiate Schools of Architecture, publication, 1990, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 1)
    Publication entitled "Status of Faculty Women in Architecture Schools Survey Results and Recommendations," 1990.
  - Baptista, Angela, drawings, 1983, Extent: 0.3 cubic feet (Box 10)
    Architect of Carvalhos, Portugal. Materials consist of six sets of architectural drawings of the Vamara Municipal da Vila da Feira.
  - Bardi, Lina Bo, biographical material, 1996-1999, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 1)
    1914-1992. Born in Italy, worked in Sao Paulo, Brazil. Among other residential and public structures in Brazil, she designed the Museum of Art Sao Paulo (1958) and the Sesc-Pompeia (1977), a combined sports and arts center. Her collection includes a press release with biographical information for an exhibit of her work at the California College of Arts and Crafts in San Francisco.
  - Bassett, Florence Knoll, article, 2001, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 1)
    Interior Designer in Coconut Grove, Florida; article in Metropolis "The Soul of Knoll," July 2001
  - Bausman, Karen, biographical material, 2006, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 18)
    Founder and Principal of Karen Bausman + Associates, New York, New York. (1995-). Collection includes biographical information for inclusion in the IAWA Biographical Database.
  - Bentel, Maria A., biographical material, 2000 amd undated, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 10)
    Born in 1928. Architect and partner of Bentel & Bentel, Architects and Planners, of New York, and a Fellow of the American Institute of Architects. Collection includes a brochure of her work with her firm.
  - Bethune, Louise Blanchard, postcard, 1907, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 20)
    Bethune (1856-1913) was the first female associate of the American Institute of Architects (AIA). The collection contains a 1907 postcard featuring Bethune's Lafayette Hotel in Buffalo, NY.
  - Bevington, Christine Benglia, résumé, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 1)
    Résumé.
  - Billmyer, Dorothy Pebworth Morgan., biographical materials, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 20)
    Scope and Content
    Architect of Portsmouth, Virginia. Studied architectural drafting at Old Dominion University (then known as the Norfolk branch of the College of William and Mary). She graduated from Old Dominion University in 1963 with a B.S. in Education and in 1971 with a M.S. in Education. Billmyer designed several residential and commercial buildings in the Tidewater region, including over 200 private residences and The Circle Restaurant in Portsmouth, Virginia. The restaurant was added to the National Register of Historic Places in 2006 and demolished in 2013. Materials include biographical information about Dorothy Pebworth Morgan Billmyer; correspondence from her husband Frank W. Billmyer (1919-2014); handwritten descriptions of 42 structures she designed; a copy of the National Register of Historic Places application for The Circle Restaurant; and photocopies of drawings and portraits featuring the architect.
    Billmyer, Dorothy Pebworth Morgan, 1915-1997
  - Binder, Rebecca L., papers, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 1)
    Born in 1951. Principal of R. L. Binder, F.A.I.A., Architecture & Planning, in Playa del Rey, California, and a Fellow of the American Institute of Architects. Materials include curriculum vita detailing major projects, employment, exhibitions, publications, activities, and honors; descriptions of fifteen of her designs. A copy of the book Rebecca L. Binder, with text by Eleanor Lynn Nesmith, edited by Shawna Mullen (Rockport, Massachusetts: Contemporary World Architects, 1995) is located in the Special Collections stacks as well as in the Art + Architecture library. NA737.B495 N47 1995
  - Biriukova, Alexandra, biographical material, 1969, 1980-1987, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 1)
    1895-1967. Russian architect in Canada. Received architecture degree in 1914 from the School of Architecture in Petrograd, Russia. Exiled in 1917; moved to Italy where she received a degree in 1925 from the Royal Superior School of Architecture in Rome. Emigrated to Toronto, Canada, in 1929. Designed a residence for artist Lawren Harris in Toronto and was elected the first woman member of the Ontario Association of Architects in 1931, yet entered nursing school that same year and spent the rest of her career as a nurse. Materials consist of research notes, correspondence, published biographical sources, and card files compiled by Barbara Sankey of Toronto, who researched Biriukova's career.
  - Birkby, Noel Phyllis, biographical material, 1991, 1994, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 1)
    1932-1994. Architect of New York City. Educated at the Cooper Union and at Yale University; worked for architectural firms in New York City and was principal of her own firm. Taught at the New York Institute of Technology. Papers are photocopies of obituaries and other biographical information about Birkby.
  - Bizios, Georgia, résumé and exhibit postcard, 1996, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 1)
    Professor of Architecture and Associate Dean for Academics at the School of Design, North Carolina State University (1986-present). Educated at Colby College (B.A. Art, 1967), University of Minnesota (B.Arch., 1971), and University of Oregon (M.Arch, 1974). Former member of the Board of Advisors for the IAWA. Collection consists of a curriculum vitae and a postcard advertising an exhibit of her work at the Brooks Hall Gallery of the School of Design, North Carolina State University, in January 1996.
  - Bliss, Anna Campbell, architectural papers, 1978-1994, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 1)
    Born 1925. Artist, architect, and consultant on color and design in Salt Lake City, Utah; partner of Bliss and Campbell, Architects; and founder and former President of the Contemporary Arts Group. Materials include a curriculum vitae; photographs, a 1987 flyer for a CAG conference; three articles on color and architecture; a notice of an exhibition of a mural Bliss designed for the Utah State Capitol; and a bibliography of publications, articles, and catalogs by Bliss.
  - Boden-Archer, Dendron, biographical material, 1997 and undated, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 1)
    Greek psychologist with an interest in "dream healing" within the framework of landscape and architecture. Collection includes a biographical sketch and a copy of an article that she wrote.
  - Bodmer, Monica, videotape, 2000, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 2)
    One-hour videotape and DVD version entitled Spatial Biography and Mental Maps produced for the International Women's University, Project Area City and Gender, in Kassel, Germany in 2000. Created by Monica Bodmer of Lausanne, Switzerland and Prof. Kerstin Dörhöfer of Berlin, Germany. Includes prologue and sections by twelve contributors.
  - Bolldorf-Reitstätter, Martha, article, 1998, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 2)
    Photocopy of article with information about Bolldorf-Reitstatter in Steine Sprechen, no. 110, 2pp. 1998.
  - Bonney, Claire, papers, 1995-1998, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 2)
    The collection contains a copy of Thérèse Bonney: The Architectural Photographs, a PhD thesis from the University of Zurich. Materials submitted in application for the first Milka Bliznakov Prize, 2000. See also Bonney's report on architect Adrienne Gorska. Inventory available.
  - Borecka, Eva, biographical material, 2006, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 18)
    Architect of Slovakia. Collection includes biographical information for inclusion in the IAWA Biographical Database.
  - Bragstad, Susan, drawings, 1983-1989, Extent: 1.7 cubic feet (Oversize 1)
    Collection includes two sets of drawings featuring houses designed by Bragstad in the 1980s; a short biography of Bradstad and a biography of her mother Martha Marie Wagele Mood an artist, photographer, and teacher.
  - Brians, Audrey, papers, 1951-1952, 2001-2002, 2008, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 2)
    Principal and President of Brians and Associates/Architects, Inc., of Panama City, Florida. Materials include four brochures - one describes her firm and includes a curriculum vitae, and three detail her designs. Also includes a 12-page memoir, ""Confessions of an Irreverent Iconoclast"" written in 2002. Also has materials on VT ImageBase.
  - Brierly, Cornelia, biographical material, 2007, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 2)
    Printed material from Society of Architectural Historians (SAH) Conference Tour "Peter Berndtson and Cornelia Brierly in Pittsburgh," April 14, 2007
  - Brosowsky, Bettina Maria, papers, 1984-1985 and undated, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 2)
    Born in 1957, architect in Germany. Collection contains plans and images of two competition designs from the 1980s, illustrated descriptions of three projects designed by her firm, Brosowsky & Teschner, Architekten, during 1992-2003. Also includes a pamphlet written by Brosowsky in 2003 entitled Wolfsburg Architektur-Stadtplan: Bauten der Jahrtausendwende und die Klassiker with a city map and descriptions of buildings in Wolfsburg, Germany.
  - Brotons de la Nuez, Rosa Maria, certificate and photographs, 1973, 1986, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 2)
    Architect of Barcelona, Spain. Copy of a 1973 certificate from the Colegio Oficial de Arquitectos de Canarias, and two photographs of Palacio del Hielo, a skating rink she designed.
  - Browne, Charlene, curriculum vita, 1998, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 2)
    11 page curriculum vitae
  - Browne, Jennifer. curriculum vitae, 1995, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 2)
    Born 1949. Project Architect, SLR/Architects, Palo Alto, California.
  - Budevska-Salcheva, Nadezhda, papers, 1965-1988, Extent: 2.0 cubic feet (Box 2, Box 17)
    Nadezhda Budevaska-Salcheva graduated from Sofia Polytechnic in 1949, and thereafter pursued a career as a champion tennis player. In 1967, she joined the Sofia Design Organization, where she designed many large buildings such as hospitals and research institutes. In 1980 she established a private office, focusing mainly on private residences. The papers include drawings and photos of projects for residential projects in/near Sofia, Bulgaria, 1965-1988, a photo of a drawing of research laboratories, newspaper clippings, and a two-page c.v. in English with image of Budevska.
  - Budis, Sanda papers, 1983; 1985; and undated, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 2)
    Architect of Lutry, Switzerland. Architectural drawings and a brochure with drawings, notes, sketches and slides of "La Conversion/Lutry."
  - Bulant, Kamenova Aneta brochure, 1999, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 2)
    Born in Sofia, Bulgaria. Practiced in Sofia and Vienna. Her firm's brochure, "Emerging Architecture," features three residential projects, a carpenter's shop, and a bank designed by Bulant & Wailzer. Inventory available.
  - Campana, Ana, biographical material, 1987, 1994, and undated, Extent: 0.1 cubic feet (Box 2)